Well, I got to bleep this out, but
and he's extremely multi-billionaire.
>> Extremely multi-billionaire.
>> Extremely. [laughter]
>> Sam, I have here in front of me
a letter that I need to read for you.
So, I I open the mail and I see a
invitation
like this to a graduation. And I think,
that's not my cousin, that's not my
nephew. Who is this?
Dear Shawn, my name is Quinton Wood.
I've been listening to MFM for
since 2021. Over the last 5 years, you
and Sam's podcast has made a huge impact
on my life, shaping how I see the world,
investing in stocks, my goals, my life.
Your podcast brought me a lot of joy and
helped me through long runs and study
sessions.
You and Sam have directed my life for
the better, so thank you. I'm a high
school senior this year, and because of
the profound impact you've made in my
life, I want to invite you to my
graduation and graduation party. He
lives in He lives in Colorado. Thank you
for Thank you for taking the time to
read this and everything you do. Keep
making more episodes. Sincerely, Quinton
Wood, high school senior.
Isn't this amazing?
>> Baller.
Congrats, Quinton.
>> Take a bow, Quinton.
>> [laughter]
>> How good is that, man? I I love this
kid.
>> If you're under the age of 24, you
should do some of these things that
might sound insulting, like we said
that's endearing or I would never say
that's cute, but like you feel like that
emotion.
You should 100% embrace doing those
things because you can only get away
with this at a very for the very small
time, and it's totally appropriate and
totally awesome.
>> It's like pooping your pants. You can
only do it for so long. [laughter]
>> Well, then we could do it like later in
life, but like
you like this type of stuff 100% is
awesome.
>> And by By way,
okay, a bunch of people have written but
just inviting to the high school
graduation is so endearing. I just
thought. I was like, "Oh, that's so like
so wonderful." And Diego was like, "So,
we're going to go?" I was like,
"No, hell no. We're definitely not
going." But but I I will play him the
song and and give him the clap. This is
great.
Okay, I want to tell you about this this
business story that that
to me this is this is a billy of the
week. So, this is a
a billionaire family that I I found
really fascinating. I've been into these
like family dynasties. Last last week I
think we were talking about Cargill. And
this one is
>> Wait, can I want to try and guess these?
I like trying to guess.
>> Let me give you a couple of clues so you
know which direction you're going.
The richest man in Italy.
>> Sunglasses or chocolate?
>> Chocolate.
>> Okay. [laughter]
>> Do you know who it is?
>> Yeah. I
Roche Roche is it called Roche
something? For for Ferrero Roche.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
okay. Well, you got that pretty quick.
>> [laughter]
>> It's a lot less fun when you just know
the answer, huh?
If I was a teacher, I would just be
like, "Well, fine. Teach yourself then."
And walk out of the classroom.
Um
Dude, this family story is amazing. So,
I love Ferrero Roche the chocolate. I
don't know if you've like if do you're a
fan? Do we have Do we have one? Oh,
here. So, if for those who don't know, I
have some here.
Got this from from the grocery store
this morning cuz I was so inspired by
these guys. I was like, "I'm going to go
support their small business."
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, you bought local.
>> He's worth 32 billion dollars.
Um so, the these chocolates are kind of
amazing. They're The packaging is
amazing. If you've ever had one of
these, you really feel like you're
eating something special. And that got
me kind of interested in like, "What's
the back story of this?" Turns out this
family invented Nutella. They invented
Tic Tacs. They invented like a whole
bunch of Kinder the Kinder bars and
Kinder eggs. They invented like several
of these like really big things. And now
they own a whole bunch of other
businesses. So, I want to tell you that
the story of this this company that's
it's one of the most secretive
family-owned businesses in the world.
They do like $20 billion a year in
revenue. The founder is the the the main
guy that this the heir. He runs the
company and is the richest man in Italy.
And the way they did it is really
fascinating. So,
um back in the day this was post right
after World War II, Italy, which was
like, you know, not in great shape
post-World War II,
um it was trying to kind of bounce back.
And so, this guy uh the grandfather uh
of of this guy, he decides, "I'm going
to start
um making chocolate." Chocolate was
really expensive. It was like this
luxury item. It wasn't like a little
common thing you found at every store.
Not everybody was eating it. And so, he
starts and he the he had the form factor
wrong. He was trying to make a a bar
like a a spread. So, it's like butter.
It would be like this kind of hard
chocolate like butter stick essentially.
And his idea was like people would put
this on toast and you'll have like a
chocolatey toast.
>> And I think at the time like chocolate
was like something like it was it was
like the equivalent of caviar. Like if
you went to like a fancy dinner party,
you would see it. And if I remember
correctly, I don't even think it tasted
nearly like it tastes now. It wasn't
like
>> They've just added butter and sugar over
the years to the mix. It's like cuz if
you have like a cacao bean or cacao
powder, it's like bitter. It's like very
bitter, right? So, so you you really
have to like butter and sugar it up. So,
he he tries the bar. People don't like
it. They're complaining. They're like,
"It's too hard. Doesn't spread easily."
So, he's like, "Okay, I got to solve the
spread problem." And he comes up with a
jar with like a creamy chocolate, like a
a jam basically. And it's like a
precursor to Nutella. It wasn't quite
Nutella yet. Um but the idea was like
make it super spreadable, put it in a
jar.
And it was called Supercrema. And so, he
starts trying to sell Supercrema and
it's doing okay. It's him he's like the
chef and he's just trying to make like
delicious pastries basically. And he's
got the brother who's the business side.
And they're they're doing all right, not
great. But, over time, the son takes
over, And and the son is a bit more of
an innovator. So, first, I think the
government like bans the use of Crema in
the name, so he's got to rebrand it
anyways, and he decides to call it
Nutella. And
it was hazelnuts are a big ingredient
for the thing, and he makes it he tweaks
the recipe, makes it better, and the son
starts innovating. He gets in the lab,
and he basically creates he notices that
breath mints are great, but there's all
these problems. They come in these like
big tins, hard to carry around, right?
It's like big giant rectangle. To open
it up, you had to like kind of find the
seam and pop it open, and then, you
know, if you wanted to like share it
with somebody, they had to like dig
through, touch all of them. And so, he
creates the Tic Tac form factor. So, way
easier to open, smaller box, smaller
form factor, and the ads were all like
one person's hand out, and then putting
a Tic Tac in. And it was basically like
a Tic Tac was almost like a social gift.
It was a social icebreaker, something
you want from somebody else. So,
carrying it was almost like a a thing of
power.
>> These old Tic Tac ads are so good. If
you Google vintage Tic Tac Italian ads,
the old ads are like pretty awesome.
>> A lot of the ads would have a question
mark, which you would not normally do.
You wouldn't say, Tic Tac, question
mark, but the whole thing is basically
it's an offer to somebody else. And um
it's just a way to be smooth. Way way to
It's a It's
It's small talk for the mouth.
>> Was Tic Tac the original name?
>> Hey, I want to tell you about something
pretty cool. We have a database of all
of the business ideas that have been
discussed on this podcast. So, hundreds
of episodes, the team at HubSpot went
through, they pulled out all the simple,
relatable, interesting, profitable uh
ideas that we have brainstormed, and
they're all available for download for
free. Just click the link in the
description below. Thank you to our
friends at HubSpot for sponsoring this
podcast and putting together this free
resource for you guys. Back to the show.
Yeah, so so Tic Tac was a, you know, a
brilliant name also, and it starts
getting used in movies because the name
is just like fun to say. And um and then
he he's like, you know, we've talked
about Touchland soap, this this this
woman who who sold this company for I
think $800 million or something
recently. And what she does is she took
Purell like hand sanitizer, this
utilitarian ugly product, and she made
it look like women's perfume and it came
in different scents and it was all hand
sanitizer, but you know, it's something
small you'd want to carry in your in
your purse that looked cool, smelled
great, and didn't have like, you know,
change of just
competed in a different dimension than
hand sanitizer. Not trying to kill more
germs per second, but say your hands
aren't going to smell like ethanol at
the end of this, right? So So then then
you have the the Ferrachet like
packaging where it's like this this, you
know, these golden nuggets, these like
special things that are that are put
into this. And so just brilliant all
around in terms of like how they how
they did uh the marketing genius behind
some of these things. And so the brand
takes off. It's doing really really
well. He's an innovator. And now they're
super secretive. I think for like
up until four or five years ago they had
never done an interview. They had never
let anyone into the factory. It was like
on some real Willy Wonka They um,
you know, it was like the one journalist
who got in was like, "This is actually
less like Willy Wonka, it's more like
Area 51." There was armed guards. They
cuz they build their own machinery to
produce the the chocolate. So they
didn't want anyone to know the
engineering behind their machinery, the
recipes behind Nutella. They didn't want
to know anything and they weren't really
even using it for marketing purposes.
Like the the grandfather it all the
photos of him you'll see he's wearing
dark sunglasses. He just never wanted to
be seen, never wanted to be known. And
so it only very recently did they start
doing anything.
And so then you have the grandson, the
third gen. And so gen so gen one was
kind of like
um the pioneer trying to make it happen.
It was sort of kind of like uh, you
know, pioneers or what what is settlers
get pioneers get slaughtered then the
settlers do whatever then the
townspeople build the empire. It's kind
of that same thing. So, you know, he
didn't really make it but the son had
the breakthrough innovations and then
that guy's son
took on a totally different strategy. He
went Warren Buffett. He was basically
like, all right, inventing these
products really hard, really expensive,
really low hit rate. What if we went and
found value brands that we could turn
around? And so he went and bought
Butterfingers and Baby Ruth and Crunch
and like all these brands, acquired
them, tried to revitalize the brand and
then bring them back. And so he's built
this portfolio of other brands now and
he took like an M&A approach and I just
thought
what's the Italian word for private
equity? Cuz that's what these guys
>> [laughter]
>> This is some beautiful private equity
that I've been seeing in play here for
the last
>> That is so cool.
>> 80 years.
>> [laughter]
>> I bought a I bought a Butterfinger last
night. I I freaking love Butterfinger. I
feel old but I like I eat them.
I did. I I bought the uh the
>> and Sam having a Butterfinger or what?
>> I went to the CVS and I got the the
movie style. You know how they like put
like like movie style candy like in the
box with like mini Butterfingers. I
totally had a whole box to myself last
night. So I'm on board with this guy.
>> I don't like Butterfinger. Love Crunch.
Uh Baby Ruth.
By the way, not named after Babe Ruth.
>> It's not?
>> No. It's named after Ruth Cleveland,
daughter of President Grover Cleveland.
>> Oh, is Babe Ruth the baseball player
named after her then?
>> [laughter]
>> I don't think so.
>> Dude, you can't have two Babe Ruth I
mean that's like there's not like
>> [laughter]
>> I don't know how they got away they got
away with that. Uh this is this is
pretty awesome. Why are you
um
fascinated by this this topic? Because
it's a clearly a trend.
>> Well, I have all these like themes. So
one is like huge businesses hidden in
plain sight is always something that's
interesting to me. So like, you know,
I've been eating this but I never took
the time to think "Who made this? What's
the story of this? Why does this
packaging look [clears throat] so
different than any other product that in
the entire store? And why don't more
people do this? Why isn't like like how
can you apply this marketing principle
to another category? Like I just can't
believe people aren't doing that. So
that immediately my brain starts firing
and I start fantasizing about these
products I'm going to create before I
remember I'm already rich. I don't want
to work and I have just way too much
work to do any of that, but if somebody
ever did it, you know, like you know,
kudos to them. And then I start thinking
about
>> Wait, really quick. Uh
Rory Sutherland who we had on, he talked
about uh what's the name of the soda
that has the piece of foil on top?
You know, the Italian also Italian
actually.
>> Uh
no.
>> You're close. Pella something. It starts
with a P and it's a
>> that lemonade-y type thing, right?
>> a lemon flavored Italian soda. Is it San
Pellegrino? Okay. I thought San
Pellegrino was also water, but this is
like San Pellegrino like soda.
>> Yeah.
>> And he was explaining how
the tin over it, he's like that's a
really small thing, but they did it to
be like this can is extra clean and
special. It's
>> Fresh when you
>> Yeah.
>> Pop in the seal.
>> He was explaining the importance of
something fairly insignificant in the
grand scheme and how it and he was
explaining the psychology behind it and
and that really got me thinking and
you're you're describing the exact same
thing with the with the candy. It's
wrapped in like a gold tin.
And I was thinking about that a lot. I
guess it's another Italian company
pulling it off.
>> Yeah, so I love the marketing mind.
That's always a fascinating thing. I
love businesses in plain sight. I'm
always a sucker for you know the rich
rich man in Italy and I'm like, "Sure
don't." You know, tell me like this is
this going to be an interesting story.
And then I am also interested in these
kind of family dynasty businesses um
because
I I think it's the businesses that
really like
withstand the test of time, they have to
do like several miracles and one of the
great miracles is that it has to get
passed down to somebody who doesn't
screw it up. And what I thought was kind
of cool, there was a story about one of
the one of the generations. I don't know
if it's the current one.
Um, by the way, I'm opening one of these
up. I don't know if it's the current one
or it's the the middle son, but he said
something like he didn't even realize
they were rich until he was like 15
years old. He's like, "I had no idea."
Uh, they kept that from me.
>> [laughter]
>> It's like the four housekeepers didn't
tip you off. Uh, so I don't know exactly
how that was possible, but you know,
that apparently there was something in
the upbringing where uh, I think they
were they just spent so much time
actually working in the like factory and
and on the product that it wasn't clear
like it there was more about the work
and the craft than it was about the the
prizes.
>> That's awesome. I would love to um, I
listened to a the reason I know very
little about it, but I know some about
it is because um, Founders, the Founders
podcast, he did an episode on the
family. And it's a pretty old one, so I
listened to it a while ago. Uh, but it
would be curious I would be curious to
see like
>> you ever like to listen to Founders
without the research? MFM, we're here
for you.
>> [laughter]
>> While you're stuffing your face with
food, which is like
the that sounds great on a mic. Let me
hear you chew.
>> This 9:00 a.m. chocolate is hitting the
spot.
>> Um, dude, I had Sweethearts for
breakfast, so I feel you.
>> fasting, but you intermittently eat a
Ferrero Rocher while [laughter] you're
fasting.
>> Uh, I would I want to know like the
family dynamics. I'm so curious. I think
that
like the stories of Succession, the the
movie or the TV show and like the drama,
I don't think that is actually the
common thing. I think that like there is
a way where you could be like harmonious
and loving and also like good at this
whole business thing. And I it's just
less interesting to write or read about
that or make a movie or uh, TV show
about it.
>> yeah.
>> Yeah, [laughter]
but it would be really exciting to like
read
a book on how they do it effectively.
Uh, another family that don't that that
did it effectively is the Rothschild
family. Do you know about those guys?
>> I mean, I just know the name. I don't
know what they did in the family.
>> Like there's a crazy story where the
uh,
like the the original clan so they're
known now as like Illuminati-esque where
it's like mysterious but the original
story is I believe they were in Germany
in the 1800s and the dad was into
business and banking and he had five
sons and he seemed very loving and
respectful with them and he purposely
asked them to go move when they became
adults to different countries and do the
banking trade that he was doing and
teaching them and that is how they
became this like amazingly successful
European family but the kids were like
no he was he was a really loving guy he
like he taught us good values and and we
like doing this with them and and so
like I've been reading a little bit
about the that family as well.
>> Yeah
it's I mean I don't know if I'm ever
going to do that but I did have a random
idea recently that I just kind of like
fascinated me. So I was listening to
some interview with
the chef from Carbone and he said
something like the interview actually
was a little bit boring but he said one
thing that I thought was was pretty
interesting he goes
Oh I was always obsessed with food I was
12 years old and I was
absolute foodie I was always watching
cooking shows I knew about every
restaurant I knew I wanted to be a chef.
And you know one of the greatest gifts
that nobody really talks about right
like you want you want your kid to be
you know really good at school or really
good at sports really whatever I mean
really one of the best things you can do
is figure out what you actually love to
do in life. The earlier you figure that
out that's actually the big advantage
and so you know
>> was Warren Buffett's advantage.
>> It's Warren Buffett's it's everyone if
you read these guys they you know
Mr. Beast is like yeah at 12 I just at
11 years old I decided I was going to be
a YouTuber like I just wanted to be a
YouTuber that's all I wanted to do and
so from he's like yeah so I'm whatever
he is now 28 he's like yeah but I'm
doing this for 20 years he's like you
know it's like I've been doing this 17
years now and so he's literally just
spent more time on this than everyone
else. Warren Buffett bought first stock
at seven and basically was thinking
about businesses, money, and stocks
since he was very young. And and had
time during that a golden window. And
and when I interviewed Monish Pabrai, he
was I was asking about these books on
the wall. He had a whole section on like
science and neuro neuroscience and
psychology.
And I go, "What's something you really
took away from reading a bunch of
these?" And he goes, "We have a certain
hardwiring
that's kind of baked by the time you're
six or seven. Like your your core
nature, your DNA. You kind of know who
that person is." But he goes, "And
there's a golden window. And I think the
golden window was something like, you
know,
six to 16 years old.
And during that 10-year window,
if you found something that's that you
can obsess over and you can um
you get free rein to actually obsess
over it during that window, you will
hyper-specialize when the brain is in
this certain period and you'll become
world-class. Like you're you're the rest
of your life happens and if you really
don't And so he talks about this with
investing. He's like, "I don't invest in
companies where the CEO doesn't have an
evidence of the lemonade stand when they
were 10 or 11 because if you really If
you're an entrepreneur, you were an
entrepreneur at an early stage." Now, I
don't 100% believe this, but I did think
it's interesting and you do see this
pattern a lot where
>> have that? Did Monish have that?
>> Uh yeah, so he I asked him that and he
was like He's like, "Yes." And he goes,
"It wasn't for entrepreneurship. It was
basically for like
his dad had a jewelry business or a gold
business or something like that." He
said, "Like basically my MBA was every
day my dad would come home and the
business was failing and me and my
brother had to figure out something we
could try to get this business to not
fail, to have enough cash to be like in
business next month." And so in doing
that, he's like, "I basically got my MBA
when I was eight years old every day
helping my dad with his jewelry
business, working in the store, coming
home, hearing the problems, hearing the
inventory struggles, the cash flow
management problem. If we have all these
sales, why don't we have any money? Oh,
because there's a difference between
revenue and profit, between profit and
cash flow. And you know, he's like
learning these things without knowing
the names of them. Like they're sort of
intuitive gut learning that's happening
during that phase.
>> And for the record, you don't need that
to be pretty successful. I do think
>> But to be world class.
>> Yes, I think that that's the advantage
that the best of the best of the best
have over
>> see like oh, in the world a World Cup
right now it is like um Lamine Yamal and
it's like you what how come the US
doesn't produce players like this? And
it's like well, because at age seven he
would have moved in to the soccer
academy and he was there from 7 to 17
and guess what? He's amazing now at 18.
You know, like [laughter]
which which maybe your kid would have
been too had they left the house and
moved in um you know, to the soccer
academy at age six or seven and that's
like really all they trained and focused
on for a long period of time. Are you
willing to do that? Uh the book Outliers
by Malcolm Gladwell talked a little bit
about this like you know, at a young age
Bill Bill Gates and Paul Allen the
founders of Microsoft, their school was
the first one of the only schools in the
country to have a computer. So he got to
mess around with the computer
for free at free access to it after
school for like a very long period of
time. You know, Furkan my old co-founder
he would tell me like yeah, his dad
worked at a computer company. So when he
was 5 years old like his earliest memory
wasn't like playing catch with my dad.
It was like building a printer from
scratch.
It's like yeah, no no no joke that now
he can like build anything um because
during that golden window he did that.
Anyways, long way of saying
I've thought about how you could be
somewhat intentional about this. Meaning
if my kid shows an interest in something
I think I'm going to lean in way harder
than most people would during the golden
window and I've thought about taking
like a sabbatical year where I'm just
like going to pluck him out of school
for you know, in fifth or sixth grade
and just be like hey, we're going to
travel the world and like we're I'm just
going to develop you. I'm going to shape
you now not like when I'm 65 and I
retired and I have more time because
you're going to be the cookie's already
crispy by then. You know what I mean?
Like I got to do it when the dough is
raw. And so, I'm thinking about that. Um
does that sound crazy? Does that sound
like
>> No. So, it's so funny. Um a friend for
my birthday, a friend gifted me the
Andre Agassi book that I haven't started
it yet. But, I was asking him what he
learned. Uh
have you ever read that? Andre Agassi's
his biography. It's considered
>> It's considered one of the best
biographies and I'm not a tennis and my
friend and I, neither of us are tennis
guys, but he's like it's it's so good.
And I said, "What's the big takeaway?"
And he was like, "The crazy thing is
Andre didn't even seem like he loved
tennis. And he he frankly didn't seem
like he had superstar energy. Um like he
kind of begrudgingly did it. Uh but, he
was pretty good." And I was like, "Well,
how did he become like one of the greats
of all time?" And he said, "His dad. His
dad was maniacal. His dad like his dad
saw that Andre showed a little bit of
interest and he just pushed him and and
just went all in on it." And I was
joking and I was like, "Okay, so maybe
he maybe he did or didn't have a good
relationship with his father. I'm not
sure. But, I think that like these guys
like uh Serena Williams' dad, Andre
Agassi's dad, like some of these harsh
fathers, I'm like they get a lot of
but like it seems pretty worth it.
Like to have this like tiger dad and
this tiger mom energy. And um I was
watching uh Nadal's uh uh
documentary on Netflix. Did you see that
one?
>> Uh I've seen a little bit of it. Yeah. I
love Nadal. I love Nadal.
>> his dad was the same way. His father was
so hardcore about it and he pushed him
and pushed him and pushed him and was
his coach. And then there's this other
guy named Sebastian Coe, who's a famous
runner. So, you know, not not that many
people are going to know who he is, but
he's he had the world record for the
mile and his dad, Peter, was the same
way where they would run and his father
would be in the car with a stopwatch
timing every interval.
>> Behind every great man is a great woman.
It's like, "And an abusive father."
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> I do think that there's a way that you
can do this where you can like balance
like being a good a good nurturer and
also a pusher.
>> clarify one thing. I'm not saying I'm
going to like hypertrain them for
greatness on like, you know, hey, get
up, we're running sprints every morning.
Like, you know, whatever up the hills.
What I meant was really I'm going to
give them exposure cuz I think most
people the problem isn't that you found
what you love
and then you didn't keep doing it. Cuz
when you really love something, it has a
great amount of pull. You just do it
anyways. I think what most people don't
do is they don't really get to walk
around Costco and sample the things. And
I think that's actually the more
interesting thing is like, how do you
get somebody exposure because I would
say the vast majority of people never
even find out if they really love
something cuz by the time you like
school is such a regimented track,
right? You're spending 8 hours a day
doing the same exact things as every
other kid. Did you happen to love
photosynthesis? Did you happen to love
trigonometry? Like, probably not. And
so, by the and then and then it's all
just funneling you to get into a
college. When you get into a college,
it's about getting a job.
By the time you have a job, now you're
working and you're trying to like
pay for life. And by the time you're 30,
you're like, well, I didn't really get
that one that that opportunity to go
figure out that actually it was
podcasting that I really had an affinity
to. I actually really loved that. Or it
was, you know, whatever it is. Like,
baking. It was this. It was that. It
doesn't really it's hard to even know.
And I think most people never even know.
And so, the thing I want to make sure I
do for my kids is
get you to at least feel and see what
different what the world is. What are
what's even on the menu of options so
that you have some exposure in life cuz
I don't think the world by default does
a good job of giving you exposure.
>> You and I have a great friend, Ramon.
So, Ramon van van Meer. And um
he Ramon had a difficult situation where
he became a single dad when his son was
only 2 years old.
And I met Victor when he was, I think,
3. Now, he's actually a sophomore or
junior in college. And um
he
Ramon was crazy. Um partly he did this
out of necessity, partly because he's a
really amazing dad. And he would bring
Victor, starting at the age of maybe
seven, to these really big business
meetings. I remember he sold one company
when Victor was something like 10 years
old. He sold it for close to $10
million,
and I remember he would go to LA from
San Francisco, and he would take Victor
out of school and bring him. And Victor
would just sit like next to him, and
Victor wouldn't talk, but he would
pay attention to the meeting, and
afterwards Ramon would be like, "Victor,
what's your opinion? What should we do?"
Um and then another time, Victor has
actually been to China.
I think a couple times because Ramon has
a company now, Afina, where they have
manufacturers in China, and he'll bring
him to China, and he'll just sit quietly
and be like,
"Afterwards, Victor Ramon would be like,
'Hey, okay, so what do you think? You
think this guy is legit? Should we go
with him? Should we do this?'" And I
remember seeing that, and before I had
kids, I thought it was awesome. And then
after I had kids, I thought it was like
a blessing, a treasure. I like it
changed from like this is cool to
admiration.
To like you have gone from being a good
dad to a deity to me. Like you are like
I can't believe how special and how
lucky Victor is to have you. And I
remember seeing that, and I'm like,
"That is the way to have a kid."
>> I I agree 100%. Seen the same thing. He
Ramon is an amazing dad, and
it's not just I I think
cuz I watched that, and in the moment
you're just kind of like, well, the
if a kid is there, didn't say anything,
or maybe even after that, "What do you
think?"
"It was good. It was cool." They're not
going to give you some satisfying answer
as a dad like
"You know, Dad, I really learned the
like the virtue of hard work today.
Actually, what I saw was they're never
going to tell you the thing, but like
you just have to trust the process and
be like it's all soaking somewhere,
somewhere in the mind this experience
was imprinting somewhere in the brain in
a positive direction, and that if they,
you know, if I didn't give them this
experience, I would have in in a way
robbed them of of some of that exposure.
So yeah, I'm a I'm a big believer in
that. My kids are really little right
now, but I I do similar things."
>> That's awesome. Okay, let me tell you
another story about someone. You and I,
we get invited to some stuff that
occasionally is interesting. Most of the
time, we both say no, but I decided to
go to one of these dinners, and it was
in a beautiful apartment, and clearly
some guys there were like total ballers.
But I sit next to this one guy,
and he's very unassuming, and I start
talking to him, and he's very nice. He's
kind of like Dharmesh Shah, the the one
of the founders of HubSpot, like very
low-key. He's like, "How are you using
AI?" And I'm like, "Well,
I made a Chrome plug-in that helps you
select like which jeans fit you if you
go to a store, if you like jeans."
>> John, look at my ass right now.
[laughter]
Tell me that these don't fit like fit
like they were fitted by AGI. Three
cities don't have water right now
because these pants fit so well.
>> [laughter]
>> And uh
I was like, "How about you?"
"What are you doing?" And he like starts
explaining some stuff,
and it's kind of blowing my mind, and
I'm like, "Wait, who are you?" And he
says his name, but he doesn't really say
what he does. And the guy runs maybe one
of the most, if not like the top three
like financial services business in the
world, and he's
extremely multi-billionaire.
And he's the founder of
>> Extremely multi-billionaire.
>> Yeah, extremely. Like, [laughter]
he's so extreme, and I thought I after
he I start talking to him like, "I
recognize you. You have articles written
about you. It's where it's like this
mysterious billionaire."
>> Wait, say his name, and then we'll bleep
it.
>> Okay, so he's the founder of
>> Yes. Okay.
>> So, one of the most like sophisticated
financial services business, arguably
potentially some of the one of the most
profitable in its field, making like
tens of billions in profit.
>> That's that's almost an intimidating
person to meet. It's almost like, have
you ever Do you You know, I used to have
this old Dell laptop that when it really
when you when you opened up a few too
many windows, the fan would kick on, and
it would start heating up. I feel like
that dude's brain must just be like
that. Is was there just heat exhaust
coming off of them?
>> I'm I'm closer to a homeless guy in
terms of like accomplishments and brain
power than I am to this guy. And it was
so awesome that this guy walked into
this room. He was one of the most quiet
guys. He probably talked the least
amount.
>> you describe his calves and stuff, what
did he say about AI? He said he was
blowing your mind a little bit. What did
he say?
>> Uh I have to be somewhat vague. He was
saying He was just explaining like how
they do it for like trading and like
making financial decisions. But he
frankly he was using He clearly was
trying to talk my level, but it was so
hard without using like the jargon that
he had to use. But like at one point I
was like, "So, is your company cool? Uh
why is it cool?" Uh he's like, "Well,
I think we have a good culture. We pay
really well, and uh the office is nice."
And I look up how much they pay, and
it's like the highest paying thing
>> in the world, yeah.
>> in the world.
>> they have the most profit per employee
or something. It is like crazy crazy
numbers like that. Did they say anything
with AI that surprised you, meaning
like, "Oh, I just did I didn't realize
that was possible, or I would have never
thought to do that." Is Give me a little
bit more if you can if you can break off
one more piece of bread.
>> Well, what what he was he what he was
explaining, he was like, "You know,
we've actually have been doing this
before like it became popular. We were
doing it in this particular way, and
then all this new breakthrough
technology came out, but it wasn't like
a surprise to us cuz we've been
tinkering with this stuff." And
basically he was like, "It helps us make
decisions like within fractions and
fractions and fractions of seconds."
Like he was using these time
measurements that I didn't I I didn't
even know what that word meant. And he
was like he he he was like explaining
like how they make decisions and how
they use AI to make decisions. And um he
was like, "Yeah, like we've had data
centers. We've had all of this stuff
before. Now it's more accessible, and
it's easier cuz we But he's like, "We
built all this stuff before." It was
just like crazy that someone that is so
epic and so world-class at what they do,
they made me feel He made me feel better
than him in a weird way.
>> So, he's a great actor, too, then.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> Wow, triple threat.
>> Well, that's why I didn't want to be
insulting. I don't think he was acting.
I I think that he like he made me he was
maybe feel good.
>> Well, he he had true true charisma then
in that he was genuinely interested in
other people, not based off of like, you
know, some weird power rankings. And
when you're interested in people, that
makes them feel great. And that's a
gift. That's a that's an amazing gift. I
think it sounds so simple and very few
people know how to do that.
>> And I've noticed that with a bunch of
really successful people, the ones that
I truly like, they are so curious. They
are curious to the point where they will
uh think about silly ideas very
seriously and take them serious.
>> Yeah, uh
I had a embarrassing like reduction the
other day where I was like describing at
we went to an event or we hosted an
event and it was like, "Oh, there's all
these different people. I like this
person. Oh, I really like this guy. That
Oh, she was really cool." And then I
realized, "Oh, what's the common
factor?" It's just like I think I like
people who like me. And I was so
embarrassed by that being true, but it
was really like the
I have a very hard time liking people
who I don't feel like me. So, the
opposite is more true than the than the
first part, meaning like I don't love
everybody who likes me, but I can't
really like anybody if I feel like they
don't like me. And I was I was like,
"What kind of junior high
mindset is this?" And I didn't know what
to do with it, but I definitely had that
awareness at least. And I was like, "I
think I should not have that be the
kind of the heaviest weight,
>> [laughter]
>> you know, factor in in this stuff." Do
you Do you ever do that? It sounds so
stupid as I said it aloud.
>> No, I mean I don't think that's so
stupid. I I think that Dale Carnegie,
How to Win Friends and Influence People,
he says, "The root of everything that
you read from me is basically people
want to feel important." And if you
understand that, then like life's cream
cheese. Like life's good. And if you
make people feel important, then then
that is how you win friends and
influence people. And what's funny is
this guy and I we left the uh the the
event together. And we mistakenly took
like a service elevator. And so we get
lost in this building for like 25
minutes like trying to get out because
we took the wrong and we couldn't figure
out the signs. And I'm like
>> Were you like, "Come on, genius. Get us
out of here." [laughter]
>> I was like, "How many billionaires does
it take to find the exit?"
>> Be Superman. Turn on the laser.
>> [laughter]
>> And and then at the end I was like
I I know that like no one can find
photos of you on the internet. I know
that you purposely stay off the grid,
but uh you know, like
want to come on my First Million? And he
like
And he even dignified it with a "I'll
consider it." There wasn't even like a
like, "Are you insane? No, I I won't do
this."
And I just think that like to all the
up-and-comer up-and-comers listening
like Quinton, be humble and be nice and
make people feel important. And that is
like kind of a key to life.
>> Well, we we should tweak that, right?
Cuz the make people feel important
sounds a manipulative. What's the real
What's the way to do that that's
actually real? I would say, be curious.
If you're genuinely curious or
interested in in people, curiosity's
like one of these um you know, like
those like grandma's remedies where it's
like, "Oh, I have uh pneumonia." And
it's like, "Put some whiskey in the
pancakes and that'll do it." It's like,
"What? That doesn't make any sense." And
then it like works. It's curiosity's
kind of like that where almost all these
unrelated problems can be solved with
curiosity. I'll give you an example.
Um one is what one is what we're talking
about here, which is when you're when
you're actually curious about somebody,
you will appear interested in them
because you are interested in them and
then they feel interesting and they feel
like you took an you know, because you
took an interest in them, they uh feel
an affinity towards you. Great, that's
one. You this works with yourself, too.
So a lot of times I I'll talk to my my
trainer, my coach. And um let's say I'm
feeling bad about something. What most
people try to do is they say, "Don't
feel bad. Feel good. It's okay." And
like don't feel bad is pretty poor
advice when you're feeling bad about
something. And instead he just says
like, "Don't feel bad, just get
curious." And he's like, "Just get lean
into it. Like, get curious about it.
What is that? Why do you feel that way?
You know, um hm, has it ever happened
before?" And as soon as you start
getting curious, it's almost like the
cloud moves away, the sun starts to peer
through, and cuz your brain literally
shifts state into a into a more
childlike curious state of mind, and it
takes the edge off. It takes the guilt
or the shame or the the the
self-loathing off of whatever it is
you're doing. It's so so weird. You
would never expect curiosity to be a
cure for for some some of these moments,
of these moods, but it is. It tends to
be. And so, just getting curious about
something I I would say is a is kind of
like a catch-all,
um you know, cure for for for things.
>> And what's funny is like I was a pretty
awkward teenager. I would say I'm still
a pretty awkward guy. Uh and I like went
and like read books on like good
questions to ask people to like have a
conversation. And I even follow these
guys on Instagram how to do it. But the
best people I found was that show on the
spectrum, the dating show with autistic
the kids. And I stole so many questions
that I ask people. So, if I'm like at
like a dinner party or I'm talking to
people, I will always say, "What are
your hobbies?"
And like it sounds like such a childish
thing. You get the best answers. And
then I also say, um
"What do your parents think of of what
you've done?" Or I ask a lot about their
parents. And like they start opening up.
But like I had to like learn how to like
have small talk.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, everybody needs to, I think. Okay,
I like that. That's a cool That's a cool
story. Can I um
can I take it a totally different
direction?
>> All right, I could talk to you. Let me
talk to you about something. Um it it's
going to sound sad, and it is sad, but I
think it's like really interesting. And
uh I I have permission to talk about
this, but I think it's cool. So, you and
I had a producer named Ben Wilson. Ben
Wilson uh was our producer for My First
Million for a long time.
And he now has a podcast called How to
Take Over the World. Uh he's got four
kids under the age of 5 years old. It's
crazy. And 6 weeks ago he found out that
he has stage four lung cancer
uh where
the odds are not in his favor, but he's
got like the best doctors in the world.
So, like some crazy things might happen.
He's very optimistic. But, I went and
met with him yesterday. He he's in New
York to see a doctor.
And I wanted to talk about my experience
getting to like like talk to him cuz
this is like a very like interesting
predicament that he's in. Think about
this. 6 weeks ago he found this out. So,
in the 6 weeks he moved his house. He
sold his home and got a new home closer
to the doctor that he's going.
Uh he did like a $400,000 fundraiser,
which was amazing. He like got his will
and all of his estate stuff together.
And he's gone to like all these um
like doctors' appointments, like so many
of them. And I remember like talking to
him yesterday. And I was like, "Dude,
you've gone through so much. Like this
is so heavy." And I And he was telling
me a little bit about it. And I My
initial reaction when I heard all this,
I felt like extreme sadness. Partially
because Ben's a Mormon. So, Ben has lung
cancer and it's in his spine and in his
brain. But, it started as lung cancer.
And he has never smoked. He has never
drank. He has really never done anything
bad in his life. Uh
and I felt like I felt like uh like we
have an agreement with the universe
where we put good in and we should get
good out. And I was like, "This
agreement has been broken." And I felt
like pretty like pissed about it. And I
Yeah, I felt very angry. But, then like
I started like seeing how he was
reacting to all this stuff. And like I
would put myself in that shoes. I'm
like, "All right. 6 weeks ago
in June I find out that I have this
illness. Like how do I react?" And I was
like, "I would be I would go insane. I I
would be so sad. I'd be so depressed."
It was just like crazy how calm he was.
And what's interesting is that Ben has a
podcast called How to Take Over the
World, which is about like how great
leaders become great.
And I was thinking about that. And he
had this uh journal with him. And it was
on the title of this journal was zero to
365.
And I was like, "What's this?" He was
like, "I have a journal where I'm going
to document every single day, and my
goal is to fill this whole thing out.
It may not happen, but I'm going to work
my hardest to fill this out and make it
365 days, and I pray that there's a
sequel to this journal so my kids can
like read this. But if I can't do it and
I meet my maker sooner than I intend to
or I want to, I'm going to be really
excited about it. And I remember like
thinking like I listen to his podcast
all the time on like how to be great,
and I listen to all these podcasts on
how to be great. We just did one on like
how to be great. And I was thinking, I
was like,
"What's crazy is how much dignity and
integrity and bravery this guy is facing
this."
And I was like, "Me or you or hopefully
and everyone listening, the odds are
that none of us will face like a tragedy
like this." But I was thinking, I was
like, "In my day-to-day life, like I
react to things sometimes in such a
horrible way, like so negatively
and uh so like not being positive or I'm
letting little things bother me or
little things distract me from what's
important."
But I was like, "I really should change
that because I hope I never face
anything like he's facing." But what
I've noticed knowing Ben for a few years
is he's always been like a pretty stoic
brave person. And I'm like, "These
little things that I face every single
day, they can prepare me for something
horrible, and I hope that horrible thing
never happens.
And if it doesn't, at least I will have
like responded to like my day-to-day
life in a way that a great man would."
Because what's interesting is like
seeing him like journal about this, and
he was like show me a little of the
journal. In my head, I was like, "I'm
seeing like a great man be great in real
time and respond to like the worst thing
on Earth
in the most dignified, wise, and like
the best way I've ever seen." And it
inspired me so much, and I was just
like, what good can I take from this?
How can I be great even if I don't face
like a tragedy or like if I just live a
boring life? Like how could I be great
on a day-to-day basis?
>> Wow. Yeah. That's a great I mean I'm
that's a great way of putting it. Um
couple of things that came up.
The first is, you know, if you haven't
listened already, go listen to his
podcast where he announced it. I mean I
I listened to that I probably listened
to that two or three times. I listened
the first time I myself
I listened a second time when my mom was
in the car cuz I wanted her to hear cuz
I just thought his entire attitude
towards the situation, towards what is,
you know,
a very devastating sort of
piece of news. It it is is you have
every right to be sad. You have every
right to be bad. You have every every
right to feel, you know, any of the
feelings you want to feel and he kind of
had such a different perspective. It
made me think a couple of things. The
first was, man,
um you know, I haven't been a religious
person
in my life and
I think it's cuz
the way my, you know, just my my logical
brain is sort of like, "Well, I don't
know. There's no evidence." You know,
like there's like literally like the
definition of like
faith is kind of like believing without
evidence and I've always respected
religion but I've never felt it. Um but
when I saw his response and the way he
was like, you know, "I'm excited to meet
my maker and if you know, if God's
calling me then that's you know, the way
it was serving him." I was like, "Wow,
this is the
this is the these are the rewards for
living with like such strong faith is
that even when the worst
news hits, even when and when anybody
else would feel, you know, sorry for
themselves,
um you know, he he took it very very
differently and it was like such a
foundational thing for him. So I was
>> He said I'm excited. He told me and I
think he said in the pod he goes, "I'm
He goes, can be excited about this." And
I thought that was like
>> Yeah, that's uncommon. Unbelievable. Um
so, I thought that was the first thing
that was like really highlighted like
the virtue and the value of like being a
person of faith and how like, you know,
I've
in my own life not
I've had the luxury of not having to
have that cuz life goes pretty well
without it for me, right? Like without
having to to have faith in in certain
things.
Um so, I thought that was that that
really stood out. The second was
I think you nailed it. The difference,
you know, his pod- podcast is about
Napoleon and Caesar and these
complicated men who achieve, who
conquered. I think, you know, it's how
to take over the world. It's about
conquerors. It's about the the world
shapers.
And there's a big difference between
achieving greatness and being great.
What Ben is doing right now is
greatness, but it's being great, not
achieving something. And I think there's
a huge difference and I think
for myself and most people that we don't
really split those out.
And it it's very easy to set goals and,
you know, I remember being young and
being like, I want to be Forbes 30 under
30. This was before it became like, you
know, the
FBI watchlist. But I remember thinking
like, that would be a great achievement.
I want to have a million dollars in my
bank account. I want to have this. I
want to have that. When I was like 19,
20 years old. And it's like it was all
about achieving. And the two people
we've talked about, Ramon and Ben,
they're great examples of being great.
Living day-to-day in a great way. He's
really showing his greatness uh you
know, in in the hardest time, which is
when when it when it when it matters,
when it counts, when it's real.
And then yeah, like, you know,
I just hope that there's something, you
know, in the maybe the age of AI, maybe
there's some
some way that, you know, with the best
doctors, with the tech, with the belief,
with everything that um you know, he
does all right.
>> Yeah, and he's he's he's um he um he
like the Brian Johnsons and Andrew
Hubermans of the world, like they like
opened up the Rolodex and they put him
in touch with all these people and he's
doing all this like the traditional
stuff and some experimental stuff and
yesterday he was like I feel really
good. I feel better than I have in a
long time.
>> Yeah. So, um
>> Uh it's looking good, but I the reason
why I wanted to bring this up on My
First Million because I don't think we
say this this explicitly enough, but we
have said it before. Which is
we talk about like being rich here and
we try to say a rich life and we try
hard to like let people know that this
isn't just about money. It's just It's
It's about
defining what life is um worth living
and how it how it can be rich for you.
And I just want to reiterate that like
the million in My First Million doesn't
necessarily mean dollars, but it means
like
the first like unit of richness that you
can have in your life. And so
that's sort of my public service
announcement, but also like some of the
things that I've learned in talking with
him.
>> Mhm.
Well, I'm glad you shared that. Uh Ben,
we're rooting for you, man. Uh
Yeah, he's part of the he's part of the
MFM family. He was He was our producer
for what? Like a year a year or two?
Something like that.
>> Yeah.
>> He had his podcast and we met We met
through you You put me on his podcast.
You were like, "Dude, I've been
listening to this thing. It's amazing."
Then I remember going to the airport
and I was listening to his Edison
episode.
And it's a three-parter and I drove to
the airport, listened to part one,
drove back, listened to part two,
and then I just went for an extra drive
to listen to part three. And I was like,
"Wow, this is amazing." And I called him
and I was like, "Dude, who are you?
What's your story?" And then we brought
him in, he became our producer, which
helped him pay the bills while he was
getting his podcast kind of like more
and more off the ground, then it was
time for him to kind of like focus on
his pod. We wished him well and
you know, still wishing him well. So,
Ben, get get well, man. We uh we're all
rooting for you.
>> Yes, it was a very the I hope listener,
I hope you don't take this as sad and
I'm sure Ben's going to hear this, but
it was
the I I I I want to leave on a on a on a
inspirational note not not sadness. So I
hope you guys dug it and we'll end
there. That's it. That's the pod.